Privacy Statement
=================

Use of information
------------------

The Office of Admissions is committed to protecting the privacy and security of the information that we request online. Personal, demographic and academic information is collected and used for the following purposes:

* To evaluate and process applications for admission—see payment information below.
* To communicate directly with prospective students and applicants.
* To create the initial student record used for matriculation.
* To provide other WMU departments information for recruitment, admission and matriculation purposes.
* To comply with state and federal requirements.

Information provided in the form of email messages to this office's email accounts may be redirected—or forwarded—to another WMU office or employee for assistance with the correspondent's question(s). Personal information, including email address, is otherwise not disclosed.

Disclosure of information
-------------------------

The information described above is not shared, sold or traded with any individuals or entities not affiliated with Western Michigan University, except in the very limited circumstances described below.

State and federal reporting
---------------------------

Information gathered is reported using only aggregate statistics and no personally identifiable information is disclosed.

Service by third party intermediaries and contractors
-----------------------------------------------------

This office partners with outside companies for services, such as shipping our postal mailings and sending our electronic messages. In the latter case, visits to our website may be tracked by the company to gauge the effectiveness of our communications and marketing campaigns. Any personal information provided to these third party intermediaries and contractors is for the sole use of this office and they are not permitted to reuse or disclose that information for unauthorized purposes.

Internet form security
----------------------

When collecting secure data our admissions website uses forms that utilize Secure Sockets Layer technology to ensure that personal information is transmitted securely—in encrypted form—over the web. As with all online services, we encourage you to take your own steps to protect personal information, such as closing the web browser when finished using the site. Failure to do so may result in personal information being viewed by someone else using the same computer.

WMU's online application forms require payment via credit card, and our forms use the SSL technology mentioned above. 

Correspondence and mailings and opt-out
---------------------------------------

When you provide us with information to help us serve your needs, we may include you in our future mailings about WMU. You can choose to opt out of these mailings by simply clicking unsubscribe at the bottom of an email or contacting the Office of Admissions and requesting to receive no further correspondence. 

Correcting or updating personal information
-------------------------------------------

Persons who wish to correct or revise their information, or wish to be excluded from receiving further communications should also call the office for assistance at (269) 387-2000.

**Office of Admissions**  
Western Michigan University  
1903 W Michigan Ave  
Kalamazoo MI 49008-5211 USA  
(269) 387-2000
